

BHARGAV JOSHI
XR DEVELOPER
Portfolio:
https://bhargavjoshiportfolio.github.

CONTACT DETAILS

io/

Email: bhargavarbeit@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <u>Bhargav Joshi</u> Mobile: (+49) 1797272847

Address: Hutergasse 4, Weiden in der Oberpfalz 92637, Germany

SUMMARY

XR developer with over 2.5 years of experience creating AR/VR applications in Unity engine. Having built several 3D prototypes utilizing my AR/VR development skills, I would like to further leverage my creativity while building interactive and immersive experiences to bring to life the customer's vision.

KEY SKILLS

Technical skills: Unity, Blender, C#, MS Office, Vuforia, Hololens, Pico, Vive, XR interaction toolkit, Visual studio.

Soft skills: Problem Solving, Stakeholder Engagement, Leadership, Organizational skills, and Time Management.

RELATED WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER AT LUCE STIFTUNG

FEB 2022-PRESENT

- -Developed 6 VR, 2 AR, and 1 MR applications for training scenarios e.g. Machine safety demo and Machine repair guide.
- -Designed and implemented attractive & interactive user interfaces and immersive environments with Unity Engine.
- -Collaborated with 3D artists to create and integrate assets & 3D models animations into XR projects.
- -Optimized applications for performance and user experience on a variety of headsets (Pico 4, focus 3, Quest 3).
- -Conducted user testing, gathered feedback, and iteratively improved XR applications.

INTERNSHIP AND MASTER THESIS AT SIEMENS

FEB 2021-SEPT 2021

- -Worked extensively with Hololens to establish communication between the device and the OPC UA server, enabling retrieval of real time data.
- -Created a demonstrator application for the Hololens to visualize the movement of the toolpath of a CNC machine tool.

AUTOMATION ENGINEER

JULY 2017-AUG 2018

- -Conceptualization and brainstorming with the design team liaising with the customer to design custom conveyor systems.
- -Designing & deploying of special purpose machines and conveyor systems for implementing industrial automation, according to the customer requirements.

EDUCATION

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN ROBOTIC SYSTEMS ENGINEERING

RWTH, AACHEN- 2.7 GPA

B.E IN AUTOMATION AND ROBOTICS

B.V.B CET, KLE UNIVERSITY- 8.91 GPA

ACTIVITIES AND INTERESTS

Football, Cooking, Cinema, Hiking, Reading, Traveling.